Finding aid in the Radio Club and Student Radio Stations records CA.MS.00094
Smith College Archives
Radio Club and Student Radio Stations records
1935-2006
Smith College Archives
Radio Club and Student Radio Stations
CA.MS.00094
2.5 linear feet (6 containers)
Records of the Radio Club include correspondence, program schedules, histories, photographs and subject files pertaining to the founding and operation of WCSR. The Student Radio Station Records include fliers, advertising, promotional items and publications of WOZQ, Smith's current student run radio station.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records of the Radio Club and Student Radio Stations files were donated by members of the radio stations over a period of time.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: Series I (WCSR) and Series II (WOZQ)
I. Radio Club (WCSR)
II. Student Run Radio Stations (WOZQ)
Biographical / Historical
The first meeting of the Radio Club was held on December 2, 1947. Marjorie Boselly was appointed by the President of the Student Council to conduct research on the possibility of starting a student-run radio station at Smith. Their goals were to provide Smith students with a radio program that related to their particular interests, to integrate curricular and extra-curricular activities on campus, and to give interested young women practical experience in the field of radio. After just over a year of research, lectures, training, and convincing, Boselly's vision was realized as WCSR, the radio station. WCSR went on the air for the first time on January 6, 1949. Although the Radio Club was at first housed in a college-owned garage and was broadcast over the electric power line which followed the central heating system, it received tremendous support from the student body. It was not long before WCSR began to flourish. In the spring of 1950, WCSR joined Amherst College's WAMF and the University of Massachusetts' WMUA in the Pioneer Broadcasting System. By doing so WCSR participated in larger-scale broadcasts and combined the talents and interests of students from all three schools.
Throughout its years of existence, WCSR aired many different types of programs ranging from evenings of classical music to disc-jockey shows to dramas to interviews to campus debates and always played special shows on holidays. Club members had high hopes for the future of radio. Their plans for improvement were put on hold indefinitely when the building in which WCSR was housed had to be torn down in 1956. These ideas and plans were not revived until twenty-one years later, when in 1977 WRSC, a new radio station, was created in an attempt to ease communication problems that had arisen on campus. As college radio stations in general began to flourish during the early 1980's, the radio station went FM in 1982 as WOZQ, playing twenty-four hours a day, seven days a week. The staff of WOZQ describes itself as "student run and estrogen powered" and prides itself in playing music to suit an array of different tastes and hosting shows at various locations throughout the Pioneer Valley.
Scope and Contents
Records of the Radio Club include correspondence, program schedules, histories, photographs and subject files pertaining to the founding and operation of WCSR. The Student Radio Station Records include fliers, advertising, promotional items and publications of WOZQ, Smith's current student run radio station.
College radio stations--Massachusetts--Northampton.; Zines; WCSR (Radio station: Northampton, Mass.); WOZQ (Radio station: Northampton, Mass.); Smith College. Radio Club.
- Series I. Radio Club (WCSR)
  - Advertisers, List of, 1949-1950 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Agencies, undated (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Contracts, 1949 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Contacts, 1950 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Contracts, 1951 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Contracts, 1952 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Contracts, 1953 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Contracts, 1954 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Contracts, 1955 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Newsletters, 1952-1955 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Rate Sheet for WCSR, undated (Box 3053)
  - Advertising Schedule, 1954-1955 (Box 3053)
  - Advertising, Student Papers, undated (Box 3053)
  - Bank Statements, 1949-1951 (Box 3053)
  - Bills Paid, 1948-1950 (Box 3053)
  - Bills Paid, 1951 (Box 3053)
  - Bills Paid, 1952 (Box 3053)
  - Bills Paid, 1953 (Box 3053)
  - Bills Paid, 1954 (Box 3053)
  - Bills Paid, 1955 (Box 3053)
  - Blanket Tax, 1951 (Box 3054)
  - Broadcasts, 1935-1955 (Box 3054)
  - Cable, undated (Box 3054)
  - Charter, 1952-1954; undated (Box 3054)
  - College Radio Corporation, 1951-1954 (Box 3054)
  - Conferences, 1948-1953 (Box 3054)
  - Contests and Quiz Programs, 1935-1951 (Box 3054)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 3055)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 3055)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 3055)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 3055)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 3055)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 3055)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 3055)
  - Deposit Slips, Treasurer's Office, 1951-1954 (Box 3055)
  - Dittoing, 1953; undated (Box 3055)
  - Eastern States Radio Corp., 1950-1951; undated (Box 3055)
  - Equipment Studio, undated (Box 3055)
  - Hand Signals, undated (Box 3055)
  - History, 1947-1954 (Box 3055)
  - History, 1977-1982 (Box 3055)
  - Hours at Radio Station, undated (Box 3055)
  - Intercollegiate Broadcasting System, 1946-1954 (Box 3056)
  - Inventory, 1952 (Box 3056)
  - License, 1951 (Box 3056)
  - License, 1982 (Box 3056)
  - Officers, Membership, 1952-1955 (Box 3056)
  - Organization, 1948; undated (Box 3056)
  - Other College Broadcasting Stations, 1949-1954; undated (Box 3056)
  - Petitions, 1953-1954 (Box 3056)
  - Photographs, 1949-1954 (Box 3056)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 3056)
  - Pioneer Broadcasting System, 1950-1951; undated (Box 3056)
  - Polls, Radio, 1948; undated (Box 3056)
  - Pontiac Variety Show, undated (Box 3056)
  - Production Department, 1954 (Box 3056)
  - Programs, Ideas for, 1949-1951 (Box 3056)
  - Program Reports, undated (Box 3056)
  - Program Schedules, 1950 (Box 3056)
  - Program Schedules, 1953 (Box 3056)
  - Program Schedules, 1954-1955 (Box 3056)
  - Program Schedules, 1955 (Box 3057)
  - Program Scripts, 1953-1955; undated (Box 3057)
  - Radio Board, 1941; undated (Box 3057)
  - Radio Station Plan, 1947-1948; undated (Box 3057)
  - Receipts, 1951-1954 (Box 3057)
  - Records, Sam Goody, 1950 (Box 3057)
  - Registry of Motor Vehicles, 1955 (Box 3057)
  - Restricted Radiation Devices, Rules, 1955 (Box 3057)
  - Scripts, Advertising, 1949-1954 (Box 3057)
  - Scripts, Advertising, 1955-1959 (Box 3057)
  - Solicitors' Report, undated (Box 3057)
  - Spot Announcements, 1950-1954 (Box 3057)
  - Television, Educational Council, 1953 (Box 3057)
  - Time Service, 1954 (Box 3057)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1949-1954 (Box 3057)
- Series II. Student Run Radio Stations (WOZQ)
  - Articles, 1983 (Box 3058)
  - Coverage, undated (Box 3058)
  - Dirt Zine, 1993; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 3058)
  - Flyers (Events), 1997 (Box 3058)
  - General, undated (Box 3058)
  - License, 2006 (Box 3058)
  - Photographs, 1987 (Box 3058)
  - Program Guides, 1998 (Box 3058)
  - Promotional Pieces, 1998 (Box 3058)